So? According to Nanase,
you want my class's help.
Not quite.
I told her I'm willing
to work with your class.
No hierarchy. An alliance of equals.
Gotcha.
So you're not gonna bring up the
fact that you're a year ahead of us.
Smart of you not to try
playing the senpai card.
I recognize that there are
a significant number of first-years who
don't care if their classmates struggle.
But moving forward, you'll inevitably
reach a point when you'll need their aid.
"So let's work together to
make sure no one fails"?
Okay to assume that you're
Class 2-D's leader?
You're free to see things that way.
Then as leader, I'll give you a warning.
I didn't come here to work with you
under your so-called "equality."
What are you hoping for, then?
Did you think I would
pay you private points?
Yeah. Damn straight you'll pay.
That's the only way this goes anywhere.
I'm afraid I must repeat myself.
My proposal is an alliance of equals.
It would be inappropriate for either
side to offer payment to the other.
In that case...
I guess I'll just be going, then.
Classroom of the Elite 4th Season 2nd Year 1st Term
#4 To Whom the Blade Turns
Wait!
Hosen-kun, I think you should listen
to what Horikita-senpai has to say.
Don't see why I should bother.
I do.
At this rate, our class
will be unable to unify.
What are you, stupid?
There's not a damn thing I get
out of agreeing to her offer.
I don't think your strategy is a bad one—
intentionally staying neutral and
passing on early negotiations
to give us a better negotiating position.
Tell me one thing I get out
of working with Horikita here.
Trust.
Trust, huh?
Bunch of head-in-the-clouds
bullshit, if you ask me.
If you turn the second-years
against you now,
and a similar test comes up in the future,
we may end up unable to secure partners,
no matter how many points we offer.
You think I'm scared of
eating the penalty for that?
I'm sure the penalty itself
wouldn't be a problem.
But what if the partner you end
up with intentionally does poorly?
You wouldn't be able to avoid expulsion.
You think someone here has the balls
to get expelled to take me down?
In this school, it seems there's a
system known as protection points.
Yes, they're a special kind
of point that allows you
to nullify expulsion a single time.
If the partner you end up
with has a protection point,
they could excise you from the school
without any risk to themselves.
Which means it's best to establish
trust now, while we can.
I get it.
You idiots rubbed a couple
brain cells together
to figure out a way to threaten me.
Sorry to ruin your sad excuse for a plan,
but I'm not doing anything as equals.
What do you expect to do, then?
We won't change our perception
of our classes as equals.
Yeah, you made that clear.
But I don't think we'd
actually be equal at all.
If you're so sure, then for my reference,
what is it that you propose?
A million private points.
Hand it over to me as collateral.
If I need your help for something
later, I'll gladly pay it all back.
If "trust" is so important to you,
that's not such a big ask, is it?
Hosen skillfully got
his offer on the table.
He's more than just a musclehead.
Like Ryuen, he's capable
of rather devious scheming.
I acknowledge the logic of your proposal.
But I can't agree to those terms.
Gotcha. Too bad.
I thought I'd be generous
and toss you a lifeline,
but I guess we've hit a roadblock again.
It appears so.
You son of a—
Don't do it, Sudo-kun!
What do you expect me to do?!
If you're that upset about
reaching an impasse,
you should have come
up with a better idea.
Let's go.
You sure about this?!
Are you sure about this, Hosen-kun?
Hold up.
I won't change my position as long as you
insist on making unreasonable demands.
Fine, gotcha.
I'll order my class to pair up with yours.
So give me some points.
Two million.
Two million?
You've shown your true colors.
It's the only way for your
class to avoid expulsion.
You won't gain anything by cheaping out.
This is getting us nowhere.
Fine, fine. I'll consider your offer.
That's quite a sudden change of heart.
Why wouldn't I try to squeeze out
the best terms for myself first?
Then you'll accept my terms
for an alliance of equals?
Yeah. Let's talk it out, no more violence.
But people might see us here.
Let's go somewhere else.
Very well. I'll give you ten minutes.
Gotcha. I'll show you to the spot.
Our offer on the table hasn't changed.
Yeah, so mine is...
Three million.
Hand it straight to me, and I'll
save you dumb assholes right now.
You're screwing with us!
Nah, I'm dead serious.
I wouldn't have reopened
negotiations otherwise.
It was a mistake to even entertain this.
Suzune!
What are you—
Let's see how much fight
you've got in you.
You're on.
I won't hold back against an
asshole who'd hurt Suzune!
What... What do you think you're doing?!
Horikita-senpai.
I believe things at this school have
changed a bit from how they were before.
We first-years know the current
situation better than you do.
What are you talking about?
A few representatives of
the first-years received
an explanation directly
from President Nagumo—
that, this year, he was going to make
the school even more of a meritocracy.
That's ridiculous!
He's even allowing fights
between students?!
Hey, Sudo. Have a look
at Horikita over there.
She looks pretty damn pissed.
Y-You...
He has far more real-life
fighting experience than Sudo.
I see. That's why even Ryuen didn't
want to get physical with him.
So...
You wanna go strength for strength?
Fighting like this isn't helping anyone!
Does Hosen really think he can gain
the upper hand through sheer violence?
No, I don't think he's that stupid.
Then by starting this fight...
What does Hosen hope to accomplish?
Well, your big, strong bodyguard
is down for the count.
Did you think you could break
our spirits with violence?
I'm gonna beat you down so hard,
you'll be begging me to
let you sign an agreement.
Very well. Then I'll stop you myself.
Ain't that something?
If you wanna show me what you've got...
I'll be happy to see it!
Pretty nice moves, I gotta say!
S-Suzune!
Hey, Horikita.
Let's make an agreement.
You give me five million.
Then all of this ends.
Th-This is absurd.
Ayanokoji-kun, call the teachers!
Wouldn't do that if I were you.
Unless you want her
injuries to get way worse.
Horikita, I'm giving you one last chance.
Agree to my terms and get
me the points I want,
or I'll kill Ayanokoji.
What in the world are you...
If you don't agree, I'll skewer Ayanokoji.
And that's on the light end of
things I'd do to get points.
That's enough!
I've made up my mind!
I refuse to accept your methods!
Clear out, Nanase. I'm doing this.
I'm sorry, Horikita-senpai.
You were never going to be able to
make an agreement with Hosen-kun.
You came up with the alliance idea
based on the things Hosen-kun said to you.
But it was all just bait to get you here.
Shut your damn mouth already.
If I take down Ayanokoji,
our class gets a huge deposit.
You know how far that'll put us ahead.
That's true.
But I haven't yet determined
if Ayanokoji-senpai is worthy
of being targeted that way!
You think I give a damn what you think?
If you're gonna try to stop me,
you can get the hell out!
Now...
Let's go, Ayanokoji!
You... Ayanokoji...
This knife—this petty knife—
is the one that I bought.
What're you talking about?
You'd lure us out here and
escalate things into a fight.
After seeing my classmates
hurt, I'd fly into a rage
and stab you with a knife
I happened to bring with me.
That's the sequence of events
you wanted to paint, right?
That's not how you hold a knife
when you want to stab someone else.
You even turned the blade upside-down
so it would look like I stabbed you.
And after figuring that out, you were
crazy enough to come let me stab you?
It was the best way to get you to stop.
Besides, you did the same thing.
You expected to leave
this fight badly injured.
It seems there's some kind
of special test in play here,
issued only to certain members
of the first-year class.
And the object of that test...
is to get me expelled.
How'd you know this was your knife?
I've done some investigating of my own.
As of yesterday,
I was the only one who'd bought
a knife of this particular make.
What the hell?
Who the hell are you?!
What to do now, then?
Even if it is my knife,
you're the one who stabbed me.
If you can't talk your way out of
this, you'll be expelled, Hosen.
So you planned that part out, too...
Ayanokoji!
A-Are you all right?
I'm fine.
How much did you know?
My suspicions first arose when I went
shopping at the mall with Amasawa.
Amasawa-san? She's involved in this?
Yes. A clerk there saw another student
stop Hosen from buying the same knife.
You're the one who thought
up the general plan,
but Amasawa's the one who refined it.
She knew it would be best if the
knife used was one I'd bought myself.
And her coming to my apartment
to find her hair tie was a convenient
excuse to steal the knife.
She was careful not to get
her fingerprints on it
before giving it to you.
It was a damn mistake to work
with a woman I barely knew.
No, Amasawa's the reason
your plan got this far.
It would have fallen apart
much sooner without her.
Hosen, I'm willing to keep
this just between us.
The hell do you mean by that?
In exchange, I have two requests.
One, I want the Class Ds to form
an alliance on equal footing.
Two, I want you to be my partner
on the upcoming special test.
Hosen is my ideal partner.
It's hard to imagine
a White Room student being willing
to attract so much attention.
Nice, nice work, Ayanokoji-senpai.
I've never gone toe-to-toe with
someone who excited me like this.
I can see it wouldn't be any fun to
beat you into line with my fists.
I'll kill you sooner or later,
so look forward to that.
The next Monday, Nanase and Horikita
negotiated an equal alliance,
and all partnerships were established.
We completed the special
test without issue,
and on May 1st,
the results were announced.
Special Test  Results
Math
Class D
Ayanokoji Kiyotaka
Horikita Suzune
Yukimura Teruhiko
Wang Mei-yu
Ishikura Kayoko
I won't make excuses.
As frustrating as it is,
I've been forced to acknowledge
your superiority twice in a row.
I admit defeat.
More importantly, regarding Nanase-san...
So your friendly advances toward
us were all part of the act?
I really did want to work
with you, Horikita-senpai.
However...
The plan to take down Ayanokoji-senpai
was still the priority.
Why would you do that?
"Ayanokoji Kiyotaka of Class 2-D."
"Any student responsible for expelling him
will be awarded
20 million private points."
That is the special test we were given.
What the hell is that?
Who issued such a ridiculous test?
I've told you what you need to know.
Ayanokoji-senpai will know
to be extremely cautious around
first-years aside from us.
I'm going to need more than that from you!
You hurt Ayanokoji—
It's fine.
What she's told us about the
situation is more than enough.
Still, that's not the only
reason I helped Hosen-kun.
I also didn't believe
that Ayanokoji-senpai was
worthy of this school.
If what she said is true...
There you are, Ayanokoji.
I'll head back for now.
We'll speak another day about
our test score agreement.
How can I help you?
Acting Chairman Tsukishiro
wants to see you.
April has reached its end.
Have you figured out which is
the student who was sent here?
Unfortunately not.
You admitted that very easily.
I don't want to make any
declarations unless I'm sure.
I see.
That means they've integrated very well.
I haven't sensed the unique
presence of a White Room student.
They've covered their scent completely.
These last few months,
they've been put through a curriculum
to blend in perfectly with
high school students, I'm told.
The fact that you couldn't
identify them at a glance...
I'll count that as a victory for now.
You're free to leave now.
Did you encounter unexpected
trouble with them?
What makes you think that?
You wanted the White Room
student to have me expelled,
but they didn't follow through.
That's the only explanation
I can think of.
That's certainly an interesting theory.
Very well. I admit it.
The student in question ignored
the plan I laid out for them.
Be careful, Ayanokoji-kun.
The choice to bring the
White Room student here...
was not my decision.
There's a chance the higher-ups
are plotting something.
Tsukishiro and the White Room student
aren't a united front, then.
Or was that another lie to throw me off?
And if that student is ignoring
even your father's directives,
a day may come when you wish
you had settled for expulsion.
The jealousy and hatred the
student feels toward you,
the White Room's masterpiece,
are unrelenting.
What will they do to you
if left to their own devices?
I shudder just thinking about it.
Special Test  Overall Rankings
1st         Class 2-A                 Average 725 points
2nd         Class 2-C                Average 673 points
3rd         Class 2-D                Average 640 points
4th         Class 2-B                 Average 621 points